Now in this lecture we are going to focus on the 7th key architectural decision which is
selection of generic compute and orchestration layer and here we have three options AWS Lambda,
EC2 and ECS and remember from the exam perspective the main focus is going to be on AWS Lambda.
Now we know that EC2 is mainly a virtual server and if you see in terms of the responsibilities
in managing various layers of EC2 so we have the physical server here which is basically just the
hardware and then you have the host OS which can be either windows or Linux and then we have the
hypervisor layer and AWS mainly uses AWS nitro systems and all these layers are AWS managed.
And then you can see we have three virtual machines here so we have the guest OS and on top of this
virtual machine you can write your application logic. Now if you can quickly look at some of the
features for EC2 so first in terms of architecture we already discussed it's a virtual machine
in terms of the management so customer manages the guest OS patching security scaling.
Now in terms of pricing model for EC2 you will be charged per hour or per second for running
provision instances and there are different type of instances on demand reserved spot options
and here we will not go into those details because this is not really relevant from the exam
perspective. Now in terms of the execution limit this is designed for long running applications
and why I have highlighted here is that in terms of the Lambda function the execution limit is 15
minutes if the Genia application logic needs to run for more than 15 minutes then AWS Lambda is not
the right service so then either you have to look at EC2 or ECS which are more long running
applications. Now in terms of scaling you can either manually scale an EC2 instance or you can
use an auto scaling group and typically it also includes an application load balancer.
Now let's go ahead and discuss the important topic on the use cases for EC2 from the Genia
perspective. First is the Genia orchestration and prompt assembly. Now if we take a look at our
previous example where we had discussed about the summarization of application logs so a typical
generative air architecture with EC2 instance this is what it's going to look like. We will have the
end user who will send the prompt to the application load balancer which will redirect it to the
EC2 instance and then you could have some code written on EC2 instance which does the orchestration
logic for that Genia app. So maybe the logs are stored in the S3 so we'll fetch the logs from S3
and then along with the prompt send it to the Amazon bedrock service it gets a response maybe
the response is stored in the S3 bucket so it takes that link and sends it back to the end user.
So you can write all that orchestration logic. Next it can also help you prepare the prompts
so maybe you have the user input and then you add some system prompts and some other details
and send that request to either to the bedrock or SageMaker Jupso. So that's how you can write your
orchestration logic. Now the second key scenario where you can use EC2 instances for Genia application
is LLM training and hosting. So let's say you want to build your own domain specific foundation
model from scratch and there is an example if you just go and Google you'll see there's Bloomberg
GPT which has been developed by Bloomberg from scratch or you can also take an open source model
like from LAMA and then further train and deploy it. So how does EC2 come into play? So what AWS
has done is they have this purpose built machine learning chips. So in summary can think of AWS
training as type of EC2 instance which can be used for training your foundation models
and then you can use AWS infrastructure for deploying the models. So from the console you can
see I'm on the EC2 service and when I did a search on the AMIs you can see here hugging face
neuron deep learning AMI hugging face neuron deep learning AMI makes it easy to use Amazon EC2
infrastructure and training instances. Okay so we'll discuss LLM training and hosting and then
you can also use EC2 for model fine tuning and experimentation. We will not discuss retrieval
augmented generation or right pipelines now and as we go ahead and later learn about rag and
vector databases and chunky. So there are a lot of vector databases that are open source
or you have open source frameworks like Lang chain, Langra, etc which can help you in chunky
and some other other processes within a rag pipeline. So if you want to use those open source
frameworks or open source vector DBs then you can host it on EC2 instance. So in summary it can
be used for any long running inference services. Okay so that's pretty much it from this lecture
I will see in the next lecture thank you.